Luke Porupski

Software Engineer

■ L.porupski@outlook.com/ +1 724 557-4800

lukeporupski.com

in linkedin.com/in/lukeporupski/

EXPERIENCE

Backend + iOS Engineer | Jan 2021 - Jun 2021 Pixelect

- Developed and released SwiftUI iOS application for ML-based aesthetic analysis and emotional sentiment inference of photos.
- Implemented entire backend architecture: authentication (Cognito), storage (S3, DynamoDB, ElasticSearch), api (GraphQL), and a web service (ECS, API Gateway). Deployed & managed with Terraform.

Quant Engineer | Jan 2021 - Present

- Developed novel convolutional neural network model using TensorFlow for predicting short term market movements with over 70% buy signal accuracy in live trading.
- Automated data acquisition, model training and high frequency trading via Python to create a fully autonomous platform.

Software Engineer | Aug 2018 - Jan 2021

Capital One

Full Stack

- Developed scalable schema-driven declarative architecture for Angular to simplify a required developer process by multiple days.
- Delivered framework agnostic web components to promote reusability across internal platforms.
- Integrated and managed A/B testing to optimize UX.
 ios
- Delivered accessible and secure user experiences while also becoming a key coordinator with internal design & testing teams.

Undergraduate Research | Oct 2016 - May 2018

• Leveraged Swift, OpenCV and svm modeling for emotional sentiment prediction on 50,000+ geotagged images to provide mood-based location recommendations via iOS application.

Software Engineer Internship | May 2017 - Aug 2017 Capital One

 Developed efficient Go-based web application for processing large scale data migrations between ElasticSearch and InfluxDB.

Software Engineer Internship | May 2016 - Aug 2016 Siemens

• Implemented full home screen interface redesign for C# application to improve accessibility, simplicity, and performance.

EDUCATION

The Pennsylvania State University

B.S. in Computer Science, 3.59 GPA

May 2018 | University Park, PA

SUMMARY

Full stack engineer with extensive iOS experience. Particularly passionate about image processing & backend development.

SKILLS

Languages

Advanced with

<u>Javascript + Typescript</u> <u>Python</u> <u>Swift + SwiftUI</u>

Go Rust

Familiar with

Frameworks + Libraries

ReactTensorFlowOpenCVAngularNode.jsNext.js

Tools + Technologies

AWS ElasticSearch
GraphQL Docker
Terraform

Areas of Expertise

Full Stack Development
Image Processing
iOS Development

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Solutions
Architect - Associate